We need to talk about the silent genocide happening in Congo. The exploitation of Congolese
people has claimed millions of lives and the media is not talking about it at all. In fact,
around every hour 48 women are sexually assaulted, 6 million Congolese people have lost their lives
over the past decade, and millions more have been displaced all so the Western world can
continue to benefit off of Congo's natural resources like cobalt. The land of Congo has
the largest amount of cobalt, which is a critical mineral used in technology. Western nations like
the US, the UK and France have given military and financial aid to groups in Rwanda and Uganda
to invade cobalt-rich areas. And because of these invasions, Congolese people are either killed
or enslaved and forced to mine cobalt, which includes pregnant women and children. Genocides
and crimes against humanity that take place in Africa are never covered in the media as much as
other events.